Wayne D. Bloss

Summary

Senior developer and manager with 15+ years experience developing web, desktop and mobile applications. My areas of expertise are in ASP.NET, C#, JavaScript, SQL Server and VB which I learned growing up. Within the JavaScript world I have experience with Angular.js, Express.js, jQuery, Node.js, and React/Redux. Have experience managing small teams and large projects.

Experience

April 2014 – Present

Consulting / Freelance

Remote / on site (NJ)

Software Developer

- Currently building a multi-tenant, multi-lingual CRM framework including dynamic forms using React/Redux, ASP.NET, SQL Server and Node.js/Express.
- Created a field-worker task-management mobile app for National Field Network, Inc. with Angular and Ionic/Cordova along with a back-end web management system in Angular, ASP.NET and SQL Server including a form-builder to make forms for the mobile app.
- Completed several projects for Jersey Central Management including custom CRM style web applications built with Knockout, Bootstrap, jQuery, ASP.NET Web API and SQL Server 2012.
- Integrated AngularJS and Twitter Bootstrap into an ASP.NET MVC (v5) project to enable clients
 .NET developers to take advantage of ng-grid, client-side data-binding and Bootstrap CSS styles.
- Worked with a client to bring complex Google Maps features into their service-oriented web application including multi-point routing, geocoding and custom CSS styled markers.
- Worked with clients to teach developers how to setup and use Git and Github on Windows via multiple Git clients (MSysGit command line, TortoiseGit, SourceTree and Github for Windows).

Aug 2012 – April 2014

Direct Success, Inc.

Wall, NJ

Software Developer

- Primary developer tasked with building out the company's new Specialty Pharmacy department infrastructure and reporting systems.
- Integrated CPR+ pharmacy CRM software with the company's High Volume Fulfillment application using SQL Server 2008 R2, SQL Server 2005, ASP.NET, C# and .NET 4.0.
- Designed and implemented a data driven system for producing combined Shipping and Prescription labels for fulfillment using C#, WinForms, iTextSharp and the UPS Shipping API.
- Created an ad-hoc Excel template and reporting system used by the majority of the company staff to access reports. Technologies used: C#, WinForms, T4, EPPlus, SQL Server 2012.
- Created over 125 reports for pharmacy sales, data entry, patient tracking, inventory, fulfillment, auditing and other operations.
- Built a system for other IT users to analyze and work through sets of bugs scraped from a large client's web-based bug tracking system.
- Designed and implemented a number of utility programs for internal operations including a prescription validation tool, a tool to automate Windows Remote Support for the IT staff, a utility to get or assign a special group membership for new patients and various other tools and web services for data import, export and validation.
- All software implemented to follow HIPAA, SOX and PCI standards.

April 2012 – Aug 2012

Clear Computing, Inc.

Tinton Falls, NJ

Software Developer

- Maintenance programming for VB6, SQL Server and .NET application components.
- Troubleshooting and support for a niche CRM desktop program.
- Dealing with domestic and international clientele.

Aug 2002 – May 2011

Dial Connection, LLC

Berlin, NJ

Software Developer

- Created an ASP.NET web portal to convert VOX audio files to MP3 on demand and stream the resulting audio to customers via Flash and optionally, Microsoft Media Services.
- Built a real-time telephony dialer monitoring service and desktop application with C#, WCF, Linq to SQL, WinForms and DevExpress components.
- Developed the company's first dedicated reporting package including a large number of the actual reports using Crystal Reports, ASP and VB6 (this was back in 2002-2003).
- Built an Interactive Voice Response (IVR) service with C#, WCF and a host of proprietary telephony related components.
- Ported a C++ Winsock client/COM project to C# and expanded the feature set to allow asynchronous operation for each of the few hundred or so API calls.
- Maintenance programming on numerous and varied VB6 applications.
- Developed stored procedures, scripts, integration packages and deployment plans for SQL Server (2000 – 2008).
- Managed a critical project to develop the company's first in-house telephony service (C++) which allowed them to switch away from an old, buggy and proprietary telephony package. Co-wrote unit tests to test the new product during development.
- Managed many small projects and trained new developers.

More Experience

Please ask about my prior experience. I have a fairly long history of work in the field of computer technology and I have been programming computers since learning BASIC at a young age.

Education

1988 – 1992	Toms River High School North	Toms River, NJ
1994 – 1996	Ocean County College	Toms River, NJ